<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GO-Global Docs – ロードバランシング</title>
    <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ロードバランシング on GO-Global Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Load Balancing</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/loadbalancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/loadbalancing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-secondary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;注意&lt;/h4&gt;
本項目の設定は推奨設定ではございませんのでご注意ください。負荷分散設定を行いたい場合はkitASP作成の拡張パッケージGGEasyMonitorの項を参照ください。
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Load balancing allows GO-Global sessions to be distributed across multiple hosts. Load balancing is required when the host resource requirements for a deployment exceed the capacity of a single host computer. Load balancing is done automatically and is transparent to the user. GO-Global can also be used with any third party TCP/IP based load-balancing service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;load-balancing-requirements&#34;&gt;Load Balancing Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A GO-Global Host must be installed on each of the hosts in the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For web deployment, if the load balancer is balancing connections to both the web server (e.g., port 80) and the GO-Global Host (e.g., port 491), each of the GO-Global Hosts in the cluster must have a web server running and the web server home directory should contain the GO-Global web files. If the load balancer is only balancing connections to the GO-Global Host, the web files do not need to be located on each GO-Global Host. Web files can be installed on the machine running the web server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If an application saves any user specific settings in the registry (e.g., Microsoft Word), it is strongly recommend that users operate with roaming profiles rather than local profiles. Since there is no way of predicting which server the user will actually be logged onto in a balanced server farm, working with roaming profiles is the only way to ensure that user specific settings are available to the user at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A GO-Global Host can be configured to operate as an Independent Host, a Dependent Host, or as a Relay Load Balancer. Please note that a Relay Load Balancer cannot be an application host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a load-balanced relay server configuration, GraphOn recommends using a license server. For more information, see the following sections: Multiple Host Environments, Three-Server Redundancy, and License-File List Redundancy.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Independent Hosts</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/independenthosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/independenthosts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Independent Hosts are GO-Global Hosts that do not interact with other GO-Global Hosts running on the network. Independent Hosts appear in the Admin Console on the first level of the GO-Global Hosts tree view as an independent node. The GO-Global setup program configures hosts to operate as Independent Hosts. GO-Global clients can connect to Independent Hosts directly by specifying the name or IP address of the server in the Connection dialog or the location box of a web browser.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients can also connect to Independent Hosts through a third-party network load balancer that distributes client connections among several servers. However, session reconnect is not supported in the latter configuration and must be disabled.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Application Publishing Service is not running on a host, the host’s icon will be red. If the administrator does not have rights to access the host, the host’s icon will be yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-2-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-2-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Relay Load Balancers</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/relayloadbalancers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/relayloadbalancers/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A Relay Load Balanceris a GO-Global Host that provides centralized control over one or more hosts. Relay Load Balancers maintain client connections and distribute GO-Global sessions across a set of load-balanced application hosts. Relay Load Balancers appear in the Admin Console on the first level of the list of &lt;strong&gt;All Hosts&lt;/strong&gt; as nodes with one or more Dependent Hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-configure-a-go-global-host-to-operate-as-a-relay-load-balancer&#34;&gt;To configure a GO-Global Host to operate as a Relay Load Balancer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the desired host from the list of &lt;strong&gt;All Hosts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Tools | Host Options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Configuration&lt;/strong&gt;tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type the name or IP address of the computer in the &lt;strong&gt;Relay Load Balancer address&lt;/strong&gt; box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A message box is displayed indicating that the change will not take effect until the &lt;strong&gt;GO-Global Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; on the Relay Load Balancer has been restarted. Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop and restart the &lt;strong&gt;GO-Global Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; from the Services option in the Control Panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After configuring a host to run as a Relay Load Balancerwith one or more dependent hosts, GO-Global load-balances client connections and ensures that sessions start successfully. If a session fails to start on the selected host, the Relay Load Balancer selects another host and tries again until it finds one that can support the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a Relay Load Balancer environment, be sure the same &lt;strong&gt;Log Folder&lt;/strong&gt; path for the Relay Load Balancerexists on the dependent hosts. Otherwise, the &lt;strong&gt;Sign In&lt;/strong&gt; dialog will not appear when users attempt to sign in to GO-Global. Create a log directory on the C: drive of each Relay Load Balancer (e.g.,&lt;code&gt;C:\Data\APS_LOGS&lt;/code&gt;) or use &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\GraphOn\GO-Global\Log&lt;/code&gt; which already exists on the dependent host.Make sure this same path exists on the dependent host. In addition to changing the &lt;strong&gt;Log Folder&lt;/strong&gt; path in the Admin Console, the &lt;code&gt;\Log\Codes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\Log\Templates&lt;/code&gt; directories must be copied to the new location.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;参照&lt;/h4&gt;
When a Relay Load Balanceris selected in the Admin Console, the number of processes running on all dependent hosts is not listed in the Admin Console&amp;rsquo;s status bar.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Relay Load Balancerrequires a minimum of 512MB of RAM. For most deployments and for best results, 1GB with a multiprocessor server is recommended. Depending on the number of dependent hosts attached to the Relay Load Balancer, more RAM may be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory and CPU requirements for the dependent hosts are determined by the applications that are published and the number of users accessing the system. In general, a dependent host can support 12 &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; users/500 MHz CPU and 25 &amp;ldquo;light&amp;rdquo; users/500 MHz CPU. (&amp;ldquo;Heavy&amp;rdquo; is defined as a user running one or more large applications with continuous user interaction. &amp;ldquo;Light&amp;rdquo; is defined as a user running one application with intermittent user interaction.)&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Dependent Hosts</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/dependenthosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/dependenthosts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A dependent host is a GO-Global Host that is connected to a Relay Load Balancer. GO-Global clients cannot connect directly to dependent hosts. Instead, they connect to the associated Relay Load Balancer, and the Relay Load Balancer selects one of the connected servers to host the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-configure-a-go-global-host-to-operate-as-a-dependent-host&#34;&gt;To configure a GO-Global Host to operate as a dependent host&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the desired host from the list of &lt;strong&gt;All Hosts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Tools | Host Options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Configuration&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Application Host.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Dependent Host.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type the name or IP address of the Relay Load Balancer in &lt;strong&gt;Relay Load Balancer address&lt;/strong&gt; edit box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A message box is displayed indicating that the change will not take effect until the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; has been restarted. Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop and restart the &lt;strong&gt;GO-Global Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; from the Services option in the Control Panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Application Publishing Service is restarted, the dependent host will appear beneath the Relay Load Balancer in the Admin Console&amp;rsquo;s list of GO-Global Hosts. A dependent host with a yellow x indicates that the host has been &amp;ldquo;orphaned;&amp;rdquo; in other words, that its Relay Load Balancer has gone down. If a host&amp;rsquo;s icon has a red X, the administrator does not have administrative rights on the host. If the host&amp;rsquo;s icon has a red X and is grayed out, the host is no longer running the Application Publishing Service or it has been turned off. In either case, the administrator is unable to access that host from the Admin Console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are authenticated on dependent hosts, not on Relay Load Balancers. As a result, dependent hosts can be located on a different network than their associated Relay Load Balancer. For example, dependent hosts can be located behind a firewall on an internal, Active Directory network, and the associated Relay Load Balancer can be located in a demilitarized zone(DMZ)that is outside the firewall. If &lt;strong&gt;Integrated Windows authentication&lt;/strong&gt; is used, clients and dependent hosts must be located on the same domain, but the Relay Load Balancer can be located on a different domain.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;参照&lt;/h4&gt;
We recommend installing the same set of applications on each dependent host and using the same installation path.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-6-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-6-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: ファームマネージャの構成</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/farmmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/farmmanager/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ファームマネージャは、ファームホストのクラスタを集中管理するために使用されるGO-Globalホストです。Relay Load Balancerとは異なり、ファームマネージャはファームホストへの接続の負荷を分散せず、クライアントとファームホストの間でデータを中継しません。ファームマネージャは、サードパーティのロードバランサを使用してファームホストへの接続を管理します。ファームホストを構成する前に、ファームマネージャを構成する必要があります。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ファームマネージャを構成する方法&#34;&gt;ファームマネージャを構成する方法&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin Consoleで、 &lt;strong&gt;[Tools | Host Options]&lt;/strong&gt; の順にクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Configuration]&lt;/strong&gt; タブをクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Application Host Manager]&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Farm Manager]&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GO-Global Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; を再起動します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: ファームホストの構成</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/farmhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/farmhost/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ファームホストは、ファームマネージャに接続されているGO-Globalホストです。GO-Globalクライアントは、ファームホストに直接接続します。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ファームホストを構成する方法&#34;&gt;ファームホストを構成する方法&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin Consoleで、 &lt;strong&gt;[Tools | Host Options]&lt;/strong&gt; の順にクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Configuration]&lt;/strong&gt; タブをクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Application Host]&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Farm Host]&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Farm Manager address field]&lt;/strong&gt; フィールドに、Farm ManagerのIPアドレスを入力します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; をクリックします。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GO-Global Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; を再起動します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-6-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-6-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Support for Third-Party Load Balancers</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/supportforthird-partyloadbalancers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/supportforthird-partyloadbalancers/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-secondary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;注意&lt;/h4&gt;
本項目の設定は推奨設定ではございませんのでご注意ください。負荷分散設定を行いたい場合はkitASP作成の拡張パッケージGGEasyMonitorの項を参照ください。
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GO-Global&amp;rsquo;s new Farm Host and Farm Manager roles make it easy for administrators to manage farms of GO-Global Application Hosts that are accessed via third-party load balancers. Using these roles, administrators can manage and shadow sessions running across a farm, and they can configure settings on all Farm Hosts in a farm at once. And when new Farm Hosts join a farm,they automatically inherit the settings of the other hosts in the farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, these new roles enable users who connect to GO-Global Hosts via third-party load balancers to disconnect from their sessions from one device, and reconnect to their sessions from a different device. GO-Global automatically reconnects users to their sessions, even when the load balancer fails to connect a user to the host on which the user’s session is running. For example, if a user with a session running on Host A disconnects from the session while at work, goes home, and then reconnects to the session from a home computer, GO-Global will ensure that the user is reconnected to his or her session. If the load balancer routes the user&amp;rsquo;s connection to Host B, Host B will open a connection to Host A and relay the data between the GO-Global AppController and Host A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-enable-these-capabilities&#34;&gt;To enable these capabilities:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a GO-Global Farm Manager:&lt;br&gt;
a. Install the GO-Global Host on a computer that is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; connected to the third-party load balancer.&lt;br&gt;
b. Run the Admin Console and set the Server Role to &lt;strong&gt;Farm Manager.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
c. Restart the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On each GO-Global Application Host that is accessible from the load balancer:&lt;br&gt;
a. Run the Admin Console and set the Server Role to Farm Host.&lt;br&gt;
b. Enter the address of the Farm Manager configured in step 1 in the &lt;strong&gt;Farm Manager address&lt;/strong&gt; field.&lt;br&gt;
c. Restart the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administrators can provide High Availability for a farm by configuring a failover Farm Manager as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a failover Farm Manager:&lt;br&gt;
a. Install the GO-Global Host on another computer that is not connected to the third-party load balancer.&lt;br&gt;
b. Run the Admin Console and set the Server Role to &lt;strong&gt;Farm Manager.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
c. Restart the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On each GO-Global Application Host that is accessible from the load balancer:&lt;br&gt;
a. Run the Admin Console and append a semicolon and the address of the failover Farm Manager to the address of the primary Farm Manager in the &lt;strong&gt;Farm Manager address&lt;/strong&gt; field.&lt;br&gt;
b. Restart the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Farm Manager and Farm Host server roles are supported by the same infrastructure and design that has supported the GO-Global Relay Server and Dependent Host roles for many years.Unlike a Relay Server, however, a Farm Manager does not relay data between GO-Global clients and hosts and is, therefore, not subject to the same scalability limits as a Relay Server. A Farm Manager keeps track of all sessions running in a farm, but unless an administrator is shadowing a session, no data from applications running in a session passes through the Farm Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-7-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-7-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: License Server Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/licenseserverconfiguration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/licenseserverconfiguration/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-secondary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;注意&lt;/h4&gt;
本項目の設定は推奨設定ではございませんのでご注意ください。
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an Independent Host is configured to run as a Relay Load Balancer or a Dependent Host, GO-Global does not automatically make any changes to the host&amp;rsquo;s licensing configuration. For example, if an Independent Host is configured to use an on-premises license that is installed on the same computer as the host, the host will continue to use this on-premises license after the host is connected to a Relay Load Balancer. This is the default configuration, but not typically the best licensing configuration. A Relay Load Balancer and its Dependent Hosts should all be configured to use the same license server(s) or, if cloud licensing is used, the same cloud license.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an on-premises license is being used and high-availability is not required, GraphOn recommends configuring the Dependent Hosts to use the license server on the Relay Load Balancer as a central license server. (See Multiple Host Enviroments and ensure that the Dependent Hosts are able to connect to the license server&amp;rsquo;s port on the Relay Load Balancer.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an on-premises license is being used and high-availability is required, GraphOn recommends configuring the Relay Load Balancer and its Dependent Hosts to use a set of Three-Server Redundant License Servers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a cloud license is being used, and high availability is not required, GraphOn recommends activating GO-Global on the Relay Load Balancer. Alternatively, if a cloud license is being used and high availability is required, GraphOn recommends activating GO-Global on both the primary Relay Load Balancer and the failover Relay Load Balancer and configuring each to be a Backup License Server for the other.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of these configurations, the &lt;strong&gt;Licenses&lt;/strong&gt; tab on the Admin Console will report the same license information, regardless of which computer is selected.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to version 6.1, GO-Global managed licenses from Dependent Hosts by default. With this configuration, administrators had to configure each Dependent Host to use a central license manager. Beginning with version 6.1, administrators no longer need to do this. GO-Global now manages licenses from the Relay Load Balancer by default. This enables administrators to add and remove Dependent Hosts from the Relay Load Balancer without having to make any licensing configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;参照&lt;/h4&gt;
Dependent Hosts that are upgraded to version 6.1 from older versions will continue to manage licenses from the Dependent Host. Administrators can change this after the upgrade by editing the value of the &lt;strong&gt;ManageLicensesFrom&lt;/strong&gt; property in the &lt;strong&gt;HostProperties.xml&lt;/strong&gt; file from Host to Relay on all the Dependent &lt;strong&gt;Hosts&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Relay&lt;/strong&gt; Load Balancer.
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Administering Relay Load Balancers and Dependent Hosts on Different Networks </title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/administeringrelayloadbalancersanddependenthostsondifferentnetworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/administeringrelayloadbalancersanddependenthostsondifferentnetworks/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When a user starts the Admin Console on a Relay Load Balancer or a dependent host, the Admin Console connects to the Relay Load Balancer and attempts to authenticate the user using Integrated Windows authentication. If the Admin Console is running on a dependent host and the associated Relay Load Balancer is located on a different network, a message such as the following is displayed:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Failed to log you on to Server8. This computer (Server4) and Server 8 may be located on different networks. Would you like to log onto Server 8 and administer it remotely?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; will return you to the &lt;strong&gt;All Hosts&lt;/strong&gt; node of the Admin Console. Clicking &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt; will initiate a special remote administration session on the Relay Load Balancer as follows:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Admin Console on the dependent host starts the GO-Global Client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The client connects to the Relay Load Balancer and starts a session. The &lt;strong&gt;Sign In&lt;/strong&gt;dialog is displayed to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user signs in, specifying the user name and password of an account that is a member of the Administrators group on the Relay Load Balancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Admin Console starts on the Relay Load Balancer. The user can now administer the Relay Load Balancer and all of its dependent hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A maximum of two administration sessions can run on the Relay Load Balancer at any given time, regardless of the &lt;strong&gt;Maximum sessions on this host&lt;/strong&gt; setting in the Admin Console and regardless of license restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependent hosts inherit their list of published applications, server settings, and user settings from the Relay Load Balancer. Applications must be installed in the same directory on all dependent hosts. Applications do not need to be installed on the Relay Load Balancer. When a GO-Global Host is connected to a Relay Load Balancer all of its server settings are synchronized with those of the Relay Load Balancer. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When any changes are made to the Relay Load Balancer&amp;rsquo;s settings, they are also made to &lt;strong&gt;All Hosts&lt;/strong&gt; connected to that Relay Load Balancer. The only settings that are allowed to vary are the maximum number of sessions and the name of the Relay Load Balancer. All other settings in the &lt;strong&gt;Host Options&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Application Properties&lt;/strong&gt; dialogs are grayed out and cannot be modified.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a Relay Load Balancer, if an application is installed but not published on the Dependent Host, you will need to publish the application on the Relay Load Balancer through the Admin Console. For example, if Adobe Reader 8.0 is installed on the Dependent Host at C:\Program Files\Adobe\Acrobat 8.0\Reader\AcroRd32.exe, open the Admin Console on the Relay Load Balancer and type this path location in the &lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; box in the &lt;strong&gt;Add Application&lt;/strong&gt; dialog.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;参照&lt;/h4&gt;
Before publishing an item on a mapped drive, verify that the drive is mapped to the same drive letter and location on the dependent hosts as it is on the Relay Load Balancer.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;host-selection&#34;&gt;Host Selection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a client connects to a Relay Load Balancer, the Relay Load Balancer attempts to start a session on the dependent host that has the lowest number of running sessions as a percentage of the maximum number of sessions allowed for the host.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the session fails to start on the selected host, the Relay Load Balancer successively attempts to start the session on other available hosts until it finds one that can support the session.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are no available hosts (i.e., if the number of running sessions on All Hosts equals the maximum number allowed), GO-Global displays a message to the user:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You are already running as many sessions as you are allowed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if the session cannot be started on any of the available hosts, the following message is displayed to the user:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;GO-Global failed to launch the Program Window for your session.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Relay Load Balancer setting, GO-Global checks the maximum sessions settings on the Relay Load Balancer and its dependent hosts. The maximum sessions value on the Relay Load Balancer is the maximum number of sessions that can be run concurrently on all dependent hosts assigned to that Relay Load Balancer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To modify the &lt;strong&gt;Maximum sessions on this host&lt;/strong&gt; setting, open the Admin Console on the host, click Host Options | Session Startup.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;relay-load-balancer-in-a-dmz&#34;&gt;Relay Load Balancer in a DMZ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Relay Load Balancer in a DMZ can be separated from its dependent application servers by a firewall, with the following requirements:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dependent application server must be able to connect to the Relay Load Balancer from behind the firewall. Please note that the reverse is not required. The Relay Load Balancer does not need to be able to connect to the dependent application server.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The client must be able to connect to the Relay Load Balancer in the DMZ.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a session starts on a dependent application server, the dependent application server opens a connection to the Relay Load Balancer. When the Relay Load Balancer receives data from the session&amp;rsquo;s clients, it forwards the data to the session over this connection. Similarly, when the Relay Load Balancer receives data from the session over this connection, it forwards the data to the session&amp;rsquo;s clients.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Relay Load Balancer generally has two network interfaces: one that is accessible from clients outside the DMZ, and one that is accessible from dependent application servers behind the firewall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below illustrates the recommended configuration for providing access to hosts on an internal network. The arrows show the direction in which the connections are made. Hosts connect to the Relay Load Balancer, not the other way around. As a result, the internal firewall does not need to allow any connections from the DMZ to the internal network. With this configuration, neither machines on the internet nor machines in the DMZ can connect directly to the hosts on the internal network. It is a highly secure configuration.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-9-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-9-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Application Host Manager Recovery</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/applicationhostmanagerrecovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/applicationhostmanagerrecovery/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Application Publishing Service can be configured to automatically restart if the service fails. For example, if the Application Publishing Service stops on a Relay Load Balancer, clients are disconnected but sessions continue to run on the Dependent Hosts that were connected to the Relay Load Balancer. These Dependent Hosts will attempt to reconnect to the Relay Load Balancer every 15 seconds. When a Dependent Host reconnects to the Relay Load Balancer, it re-adds its sessions to the Relay Load Balancer and restores any state information associated with the disconnected sessions. Clients are then able to reconnect to their sessions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, clients automatically attempt to reconnect to the Application Host Manager 5 times. In order to provide higher service availability, a failover Application Host Manager can be configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-configure-a-failover-application-host-manager&#34;&gt;To configure a Failover Application Host Manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the GO-Global Host on a separate computer, on the same network as the Application Host Manager. This computer will be the failover Application Host Manager. All clients and Dependent Hosts (or Farm Managers) must be able to connect to the failover Application Host Manager.If clients connect to the cluster from the internet, the failover Application Host Manager must have a public address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the GO-Global Host to run as an Application Host Manager:&lt;br&gt;
a. Run the &lt;strong&gt;Admin Console&lt;/strong&gt; on the computer.&lt;br&gt;
b. Click Tools | Host Options.&lt;br&gt;
c. Click the &lt;strong&gt;Configuration tab.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
d. Click &lt;strong&gt;Application Host Manager.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
e. If the primary Application Host Manager is a Relay Load Balancer, click &lt;strong&gt;Relay Load Balancer.&lt;/strong&gt; If the primary Application Host Manager is a &lt;strong&gt;Farm Manager,&lt;/strong&gt; click Farm Manager.&lt;br&gt;
f. Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
g. Restart the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export the published applications from the primary Application Host Manager and import them into the failover Application HostManager:&lt;br&gt;
a. On the primary Application Host Manager, run Regedit as administrator.&lt;br&gt;
b. Select the following registry key:&lt;code&gt;\HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\GraphOn\GO-Global\AppServer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
c. Click &lt;strong&gt;File | Export…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
d. Type a name for the file (e.g., Appserver.reg).&lt;br&gt;
e. Click &lt;strong&gt;Save.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
f. Copy the file to the failover Application Host Manager.&lt;br&gt; 
g. Double-click the file.&lt;br&gt;
h. Click &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt; to import the file.&lt;br&gt;
i. Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure each Dependent Host so it will connect to the failover Relay Load Balancer when it is unable to connect to the primary Relay Load Balancer:&lt;br&gt;
a. Run the Admin Console&lt;br&gt;
b. Click Tools | Host Options.&lt;br&gt;
c. Click the &lt;strong&gt;Configuration&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;br&gt;
d. Enter the addresses of both Relay Load Balancers in the &lt;strong&gt;Relay Load Balancer address&lt;/strong&gt; field, with their fully-qualified domain names. Enter the address of the primary Relay Load Balancer first, followed by a semi-colon, followed by the address of the failover Relay Load Balancer. For example: primary_relay_loadbalancer.graphon.com;failover_relay_load_balancer.graphon.com&lt;br&gt;
e. Click &lt;strong&gt;OK.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify the addresses of both the primary and the failover Relay Load Balancers in the URLs and shortcuts that are used to start the clients:&lt;br&gt;
a. Provide users that connect via a browser with an HTML page or URL that sets the &lt;strong&gt;host&lt;/strong&gt; parameter to the address of the primary relay server, followed by a semicolon, followed by the address of the failover relay server (e.g.,host=primary_relay_load-balancer_address;failover_relay_load_balancer_address).&lt;br&gt;
b. Provide users that connect via an installed client, with a shortcut that sets the &lt;strong&gt;–h&lt;/strong&gt; command line argument equal to the address of the primary relay server, followed by a semi-colon, followed by the address of the failover relay server (e.g., -h primary_relay_load_balancer_address;failover_relay_load_balancer_address).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this configuration, if the primary Relay Load Balancer fails for any reason, dependent hosts and clients automatically reconnect to the failover server and users are generally reconnected to their sessions within 1-2 minutes of the primary Relay Load Balancer failure. This is illustrated in the diagram below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-10-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-10-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similiarly, in a Farm Manager configuration, if the Farm Manager fails for any reason, Farm Hosts and clients automatically reconnect to the failover Farm Manager and users are generally reconnected to their sessions within 1-2 minutes of the Farm Manager failure. This is illustrated in the diagram below.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/5-10-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;5-10-2&#34;&gt; 
If users’ sessions fail to reconnect automatically, increase the value of the autoreconnect parameter in client URLs, web pages and shortcuts to a number greater than 5 (the default).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the failover Relay Load Balancer is active (i.e., when Dependent Hosts are connected to the failover Relay Load Balancer, users’ sessions will take longer to start. For this reason, the primary Relay Load Balancer should be re-activated when it comes back online. To re-activate the primary Relay Load Balancer, terminate the aps.exe process on the failover Relay Load Balancer using Task Manager at a time when users are unlikely to be connected to the cluster. When the aps.exe process is terminated on the failover Relay Load Balancer, Dependent Hosts and clients will reconnect to the primary Relay Load Balancer. Then, after the cluster’s Dependent Hosts have reconnected to the primary Relay Load Balancer, restart the Application Publishing Service on the failover Relay Load Balancer.&lt;br&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;参照&lt;/h4&gt;
When the &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; is stopped or restarted on a Relay Load Balancer via &lt;strong&gt;Services,&lt;/strong&gt; GO-Global closes all the sessions that are running on the Relay Load Balancer&amp;rsquo;s dependent hosts. Therefore, if you need to re-activate a primary Relay Load Balancer when there are sessions running on the cluster&amp;rsquo;s dependent hosts, don&amp;rsquo;t restart the Application Publishing Service on the failover Relay Load Balancer via Services; instead, terminate the aps.exe process on the failover Relay Load Balancer using Task Manager, as described above.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: あるホストから別のホストへの構成設定の手動コピー</title>
      <link>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/manuallycopyingconfigurationsettingsfromonehosttoanother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/go-global61/loadbalancing/manuallycopyingconfigurationsettingsfromonehosttoanother/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;アプリケーションホストマネージャ(Relay Load BalancerまたはFarm Manager)を使用すると、クラスター内のすべてのホストで設定の変更が自動的に行われます。ただし、アプリケーションホストマネージャを使用しない場合は、ブランド設定ダイアログで指定したものなどのホスト構成設定を、あるコンピュータから別のコンピュータに手動でコピーできます。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;構成設定を手動でコピーする方法&#34;&gt;構成設定を手動でコピーする方法&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;必要に応じて、サンプルホストですべての設定を構成します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;次のレジストリキーをエクスポートします。&lt;code&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\Software\GraphOn\GO-Global&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ターゲットホストで &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; を停止します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;次のファイルをサンプルホストからターゲットホストにコピーします。&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;％PROGRAMDATA％\Graphon\GO-Global\HostProperties.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;％PROGRAMDATA％\Graphon\GO-Global\DefaultWorkspaceProperties.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;％PROGRAMDATA％\Graphon\GO-Global\images\*.*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;手順2で作成した.regファイルを実行します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ターゲットホストで &lt;strong&gt;Application Publishing Service&lt;/strong&gt; を再起動します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;他のホストについて、手順2〜6を繰り返します。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
